(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ロボ子さんの休日
Roboko's Holiday
フクロウ〜フクロウが知らせる客が来たと〜
作詞・作曲：KOKIA
Owl ~The Owl Informs That a Guest Has Come~
Lyrics/Composition: KOKIA
ようこそ 深い森の奥
Welcome to the depths of the deep forest
珍しいお客様ね
What a rare guest you are
悪いけど ここから先では
I'm sorry, but from here on
森のマナーがあるの
there are the manners of the forest
ホー ホー フクロウが知らせる
Hoh... hoh... the owl informs
客が来たと
that a guest has come
ホー ホー フクロウが知らせる
Hoh... hoh... the owl informs
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is about to begin
ララ　ララ　何が見たいの？
La la, la la, what do you want to see?
ララ　ララ　あなた次第
La la, la la, it's up to you.
悪いけど　ここではあなたは　招かれざる客なの
I'm sorry, but here you are an uninvited guest.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
ホー　ホー　お客が来たと
Hoo, hoo, that a guest has arrived.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is about to begin.
ララ　ララ　何が見たいの？
La la, la la, what do you want to see?
ララ　ララ　あなた次第
La la, la la, it's up to you.
悪いけど　ここではあなたは　招かれざる客なの
I'm sorry, but here you are an uninvited guest.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
ホー　ホー　お客が来たと
Hoo, hoo, that a guest has arrived.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is about to begin.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
ホー　ホー　お客が来たと
Hoo, hoo, that a guest has arrived.
ホー　ホー　フクロウが知らせる
Hoo, hoo, the owl lets us know.
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is about to begin.
Good morning! Good afternoon! Good evening!
Hola! Annyeong!
そして Hello, Bo!
And Hello, Bo!
ホロライブ0期生 バーチャルロボットのロボ子だよー！
Hololive Generation 0 virtual robot, Roboco-san!
えーなんと今日をもちましてロボ子
And as of today, Roboco...
5歳児を卒業して
...graduated from being a 5-year-old...
6歳になりましたー！イエーイ！
...and became 6 years old! Yay!
おめでとありがとう。そうなんですよー。
Happy birthday, thank you. That's right.
今日はね ロボ子爆誕というわけで
Today is Roboco's rebirth (birthday),
たくさんのね ライブの曲用意しましたので
and I've prepared many live songs for you,
コラボももちろんソロももちろん いっぱいいっぱい楽しんでってください
so please enjoy the collaborations and solos to the fullest!
お知らせもあるのでね ぜひぜひお楽しみに
There's also an announcement, so please look forward to it!
にゃ！してってください。はい！
Nya! Please stick around. Yes!
そしてね ぜひ #ロボ子爆誕 こちらのハッシュタグ
And please use the hashtag #RobocoBakutan.
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドお願いします。入りたい！
Tweet a lot and let's get it trending, please! I want to trend!
毎秒可愛いロボ子のGIFとかね 写真スクショとかね 撮ってってくださいね
Please take screenshots and make GIFs of the cute Roboco every second!
そしてフクロウ...
And the owl...
「フクロウが知らせる客が来たと」を
I've just sung "Fukuro ga Shiraseru Kyaku ga Kita to."
歌わせていただきました。
I hope you enjoyed it.
いかがでしたか？
How was it?
最近ハマってる曲の1つなんだけどさ
It's one of the songs I've been really into lately.
この服とすごい合ってなかった？
Don't you think it matched this outfit perfectly?
幻想的だったでしょ？
It felt quite mystical, didn't it?
気に入ってもらえたかな？
I hope you liked it.
というわけでね この後もいっぱい歌っていくので
Anyway, I'll be singing a lot more after this...
お楽しみにしてってくださーい
So please look forward to it!
見逃すなよー
Don't miss it!
よー
Yo!
あれ？次はもしかして…
Oh? Is the next one, perhaps...
それでは次の曲に行ってまいりましょう！
Well then, let's move on to the next song!
ステージ移動じゃーい！
Stage transition time!
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Whose sleeve does the phantom flower bloom upon?
ただそこに藍を落とした
Just dropping indigo there.
派手に色を溶かすように
As if to splash colors vibrantly.
檠火の月を添えて
Accompanied by the moon of the torchlight.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling.
躓くごとに強くなった
Growing stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger.
選ばれなければ選べばいい
If you aren't chosen, then just choose for yourself.
声を轟かせ 夜の素顔の向こうへ
Let your voice thunder beyond the night's true face.
涙で滲んでた あんなに遠くの景色まで
To those distant landscapes that were blurred by tears.
響き渡れ
Resonate far and wide!
何を奏でて？誰に届けたくて？
What are you playing? Who do you want to reach?
不確かなままでいい
It's fine to remain uncertain.
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions...
どんなに長い葛藤も
...or how long the inner conflict.
歌と散れ 残響
Scatter with the song, echo!
ただ一人舞う千夜
A thousand nights dancing all alone.
違えない帯を結べば
If I tie the sash that will not falter...
派手な色も負かすように
...as if to outshine even the vibrant colors.
深紅の香こそあはれ
The crimson scent is truly poignant.
この先どんなつらい時も
No matter how hard the times ahead...
口先よりも胸を張って
...keep your head high rather than just making excuses.
抱いた夢の灯火を全部辿るだけ
Just follow all the lights of the dreams you've held.
逃げ出すためここまで来たんじゃないだろ？
You didn't come this far just to run away, did you?
選ばれなければ選べばいい
If you aren't chosen, then just choose for yourself.
声を枯らして 燃える華のように
Wither your voice like a burning flower.
闇間を照らしたら
If you illuminate the darkness...
曖昧過ぎる正解も
...then even the answers that are too vague...
譜面にして
...turn them into a musical score.
夜を数えて朝を描くような
Counting the nights to draw the morning...
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
...ringing out a vivid sound.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret...
どんなに高い限界も
...or how high the limit...
掻き消して 残響
...drown it all out, echo!
ロボ子さん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco-san, happy birthday!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ちなみになんですけど、何歳になったんですか？
By the way, how old did you become?
なんと！片手じゃもう収まりきれない年になりました！
Actually! I've reached an age that no longer fits on one hand!
えー、どういうこと？え、10歳？
Eh, what do you mean? Uh, 10 years old?
10歳じゃねーよ！
I'm not 10!
あれ？あれれ？
Huh? Oh?
6歳？
6 years old?
6歳になったの！
I became 6 years old!
そう、6歳でオーバーしてるって！
Yeah, I'm already over 6 years old!
10は言い過ぎたかな。
I guess 10 was going too far.
そうだよ、全くもう。
That's right, honestly.
え、でもあやめと2人で歌うの初じゃね？
Wait, but isn't this the first time for the two of us to sing as a duo?
え、そうだよね！なんだかんだ初めてな気がする。
Yeah, you're right! It feels like the first time, all things considered.
遊んではいるけれどもさ
We've hung out together, but...
3Dの横並びとかめっちゃ珍しくね？
Duo-ing on a 3D stage is super rare, isn't it?
めずらしい！なんか初めてなこと今さら気づいたかも。
Rare indeed! I might have just realized it's a first for us.
今さらですね。
Better late than never.
ボクも...
I also...
角生えちゃったんだよねー。
grew horns!
見て見て！
Look, look!
分かるかな？
Can you tell?
あ！
Oh!
このこれこれ！
This, these right here!
そうそうそう！
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
ちっちゃいやつだ。ちっちゃいねこれね。
They're tiny. They're so small, aren't they?
ちっちゃい？おい！
Small? Hey!
あれ？ちっちゃい？あれ？
Wait, they're small? Huh?
これ結構立派だなって思ってんだけど。
I thought they were quite magnificent.
余よりはちっちゃいから。
They're smaller than mine.
ちょっとまだあれ、鬼としてはまだまだなんじゃない？
Maybe you're not quite a full-fledged oni yet?
おっせー！先輩！
Oh, man! Senpai!
余の方がちょっと先輩かな？
I guess I'm your senior, then?
くそ！師匠と呼ばせてください！
Damn! Please let me call you Master!
はっは。弟子にしてやってもいいよ。
Haha. I suppose I could take you as a disciple.
いつか大きくなるその時まで。
Until the time they grow large one day...
育ててやろう。
I shall train you.
あー、でも今日本当に歌えてよかった！
Ah, but I'm so glad we got to sing today!
ねー、楽しかった！
Yeah, it was fun!
しかも残響散歌歌いたかったから嬉しい！
I'm so happy because I really wanted to sing Zankyou Sanka!
えー、嬉しい！この和風の曲をねすごい歌いたかったんだよね。
I'm glad! I really wanted to sing this Japanese-style song.
嬉しい！和風でいいよね。
I'm happy too! The Japanese style is great, isn't it?
そう、ボクたちシナジーあるよ今。
Exactly, we've got some serious synergy right now.
シナジーまる。角だし、着物だし。
Perfect synergy. Both with horns and kimonos.
角だし、着物だし。
Horns and kimonos.
いや、いい。いいじゃないですか。ははは。
Yeah, it's nice. It's really good. Hahaha.
はい！というわけで。
Alright then! On that note...
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、ボクはこの後もまだまだ鬼として修行を積んでいきたいと思います！
I'm going to continue my training as an oni from here on out!
頑張ってねー！
Good luck!
頑張る！
I'll do my best!
これからも続き見てください！
Please keep watching the rest of the stream!
ありがとー！頑張ってねー！
Thank you! Good luck out there!
お嬢もねー！
You too, Ojou!
またねー！バイバーイ！余だよー！余だよー！
See ya! Bye-bye! It's me! It's me!
チューリングラブ
作詞 ナユタセイジ／ナユタカリ 作曲 ナユタセイジ
Turing Love
Lyrics by Seiji Nayuta / Nayutakari, Composed by Seiji Nayuta
さあ 恋の定義が分かんない
Now, I don't know the definition of love
まず好きの基準も分かんない
First of all, I don't know the criteria for 'liking'
要は恋してる時が恋らしい 客観・エビデンス・プリーズ
In short, when you're in love, it seems like love. Objectivity, evidence, please
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First of all, I can't even solve normal calculations
要はそんな状態が愛らしい アイノー・ユーノー・独壇場
In short, that state is lovely. I know, you know, my stage alone
検証対象に興味があって 期待値を出して解けるのに
I'm interested in the subject of verification, and I can solve it by finding the expected value
感情は合って間違って 買い目のないこの気持ちは何だろう
Feelings are right and wrong, what is this feeling with no way to win?
Q.E.D. 明りょう
Q.E.D. Clear
「停止（ディス）モーション」は 相対性にして
'This motion' is made relative
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, a mellow that can't be solved even by staring at each other
ワット・イズ・ラブ 今はワン・ツー・ステップで明かそうか
What is love? Let's reveal it now with a one-two step
言葉で生み出す結末（きっちゃ）
The ending created by words
ハッタリだかならアンサー
The answer, if it's a bluff
測ったって 不確定 僕らのBPM
Even if measured, it's uncertain, our BPM
チューリングラブ ついにまたがって新時代メロウ
Turing Love, finally straddling a new era mellow
フォーリンラブ 今はABCまで分かりそうじゃん
Fall in love, now it seems like I can understand up to ABC
何だか教えとくれよ
Tell me somehow
表情聞かせてフェルマー
Let me hear your expression, Fermat
予測不能 可能性 今震えてみてよ
Unpredictable possibility, now try trembling
さあ証明しよう（証明しよう） 疑いない愛
Now let's prove (let's prove) the doubt-free love
証明しよう（証明しよう） 正体はまだ曖昧
Let's prove (let's prove), its true identity is still ambiguous
全部全部証明しよう（証明しよう） 正解があるなら
Let's prove everything (let's prove), if there's a correct answer
証明しよう（証明しよう） シンギュラリティなQ.E.D.
Let's prove (let's prove), a singularity Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい 目に見えない無理難題を
Today I want to prove this invisible, impossible challenge
A S A P 導き出したい たどり着きたい最適解
ASAP, I want to derive, I want to reach the optimal solution
何度空回ったって ぶつかっちゃったって 不思議なこのアノマリー
No matter how many times I spin my wheels or collide, this mysterious anomaly
解き明かす家庭必要条件です
Is a necessary condition in the process of unraveling it
3次元（カッコりったい）における2点 A・B間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between two points A and B in 3D (a solid)
次は感情だと思ってたのに 座標も公式も見当たらない
I thought the next thing was emotions, but I can't find coordinates or formulas
参考資料にも載っていないから キミと生み出してみたいんじゃん
Since it's not even in the reference materials, I want to create it with you
3次元（カッコせかい）における この気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in 3D (the world)
マルだってバツだって 不安にとってこうぜ
Whether it's a circle or an X, let's take it as anxiety
近くなって遠くなって 揺れてるこの気持ちの針も
Getting closer and farther away, even the needle of this swaying feeling
条件（Q.E.D.）は明りょう
The conditions (Q.E.D.) are clear
「停止（ディス）モーション」は 相対性にして
'This motion' is made relative
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸痛くなるほど
Turing Love, my heart starts racing so much it hurts
証明は今も 覚悟と増しているようだ
The proof seems to be increasing even now with my resolve
案内 もし間違いして
Guidance, if I make a mistake
最大の仮説を
The biggest hypothesis
今2人なら実証できそう
It looks like the two of us can demonstrate it now
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって君がいないメロウ
Turing Love, a mellow without you even if we stare at each other
ワット・イズ・ラブ 今はワン・ツー・ステップで明かそうか
What is love? Let's reveal it now with a one-two step
言葉で生み出す結末（きっちゃ）
The ending created by words
ハッタリだかならアンサー
The answer, if it's a bluff
測ったって不確定 僕らのBPM
Even if measured, it's uncertain, our BPM
チューリングラブ ついにまたがってそうじゃないだろう
Turing Love, finally straddling... it's not like that, right?
フォーリンラブ 今はX・Y・Zまで分かりそうじゃん
Fall in love, now it seems like I can understand up to XYZ
どこかで教えとくれよ
Tell me somewhere
確信させてダランベール
Let me be convinced, d'Alembert
予測済み 返成 今震えてみてよ
Already predicted, reaction, now try trembling
さあ証明しよう（証明しよう） 疑いない愛
Now let's prove (let's prove) the doubt-free love
証明しよう（証明しよう） 正体はまだ曖昧
Let's prove (let's prove), its true identity is still ambiguous
全部全部証明しよう（証明しよう） 正解があるなら
Let's prove everything (let's prove), if there's a correct answer
証明しよう（証明しよう） 最上階の果てまで
Let's prove (let's prove), to the end of the top floor
証明しよう（証明しよう） ああいいように
Let's prove (let's prove), as you wish
証明しよう（証明しよう） 感情全部全部
Let's prove (let's prove) all the emotions
証明しよう（証明しよう） 正解があるなら
Let's prove (let's prove), if there's a correct answer
証明しよう（証明しよう） シンギュラリティなQ.E.D.
Let's prove (let's prove), a singularity Q.E.D.
あー！
Aaaah!
あ！ロボ子先輩！ こより〜！
Ah! Roboco-senpai! Koyori~!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう、こより〜！
Thank you, Koyori!
そうなんだよ、みんな。今日はね、こよりと...
That's right, everyone. Today, Koyori and I...
...チューリングラブをこの教室で歌ってしまったぞ！
...sang "Turing Love" in this classroom!
イェーイ！めっちゃ嬉しいですよ！
Yay! I'm so happy!
僕も嬉しい。だってめっちゃ僕たちシナジーあるじゃん？
I'm happy too. We have such good synergy, don't we?
いや、本当そうですよね。我々ね、この...
Yes, exactly! Us...
...ロボットと研究者もそうですし。
...robots and researchers, that is.
チューリングラブがね。ねー。すごいシナジーですよね。
"Turing Love" too. Right? It's a great synergy.
実験体にされてる気分だぜ。
I feel like I'm being made into a test subject.
まあね、進呈と言いますか、6年前にね、こよりが...
Well, speaking of test subjects, it's been six years since...
...ロボ子先輩を作った日が懐かしいなーなんて思ってましたね。
...I created Roboco-senpai. How nostalgic.
え、6年前？
Eh, six years ago?
僕たち会ってたっけ？
Did we meet back then?
あ…そうだ。覚えてないんだった。
Ah... that's right. You don't remember.
覚えてないってなんだよ！
What do you mean "don't remember"?
いえいえ、なんでもないですよ。
Oh, it's nothing!
あ、でも6年ぶりにね、こうやって一緒に過ごせてね、良かったです。
But it's great to spend time together like this after six years.
いや、良かったですね。
It really is.
お前額縁のくせになんだよ、これ！
Wait, you're just a picture frame! What's this?!
いや、これ、ガクガクシカジカなんですけどね、額縁なのは。
Well, it's "picture-frame-shaking," because I'm in a frame.
何もかかってないぞ。
That doesn't make sense.
ガクガクシカジカですよ、額縁だけに。
It's "picture-frame-shaking," since it's a frame!
いや、今日ガクガクしてんね。
You're really shaking today.
ガクガク…動きがね、ちょっと鈍いんですけど。
Shaking... My movements are a bit slow...
ほら、出てこいよ！
Hey, let me out!
あ、でもね、こっちにロボ子先輩は何の攻撃を仕掛けることはできない。
But Roboco-senpai can't attack me from this side.
ふん、確かに。
Hmph, true.
え、こっちはね、攻撃できますよ。
I can attack from here, though!
やめろ！痛い痛い痛い！
Stop it! Ow, ow, ow!
おい、誕生日だぞ、こっちは！
Hey, it's my birthday!
攻撃というプレゼントだ！グリグリグリグリ！
This is a present in the form of an attack! Rub rub rub!
どう？これ、愛、重いですか？
How was it? Was the love heavy?
ちょっとね、トゲトゲしい愛やった、これ。
It was a bit of a prickly love.
痛えよ。こよりの愛、伝わってないか？
It hurts. Did Koyori's love not reach you?
ちょっと貫いちゃったかな？ あ、でもそれは、愛が伝わったってこと？
Did I pierce through? Does that mean my love reached you?
心臓を貫いたってこと？
That I pierced your heart?
つ、貫かれたってこと！
Y-You pierced it!
やったー！
Yay!
カツアゲな気がするけどな。
I feel like I'm being bullied, though.
え、でもさ、こより、いつか今度は額縁から出た状態で僕歌いたいぜ。
But, Koyori, next time I want to sing with you outside of a frame.
え、こよりの方こそですよ！楽しみにしるからな！
Of course! I'm looking forward to it.
そん時は、今回ね、ロボ子先輩が一生懸命踊ってくれてたんで...
Next time, since Roboco-senpai worked so hard on the dance this time...
...改めて一緒に踊りたいですよね。
...I want to dance together with you properly.
そうなんだよ。こよりにずっと見ながら踊ってたっていうね。
Yeah. I was dancing while looking at you the whole time.
本当に。こよりは横揺れしか今日できてないんで。
Really. I could only do side-to-side movements today.
手はできたけどね。
I did my best with the hands, though.
また今度は一緒に踊りましょうね。
Let's dance together next time!
踊ろう！
Let's!
じゃあ、この後も楽しんでくださいね、お誕生日。
Please enjoy the rest of your birthday!
楽しむ！ありがとうね！
I will! Thanks!
おめでとうございました！
Congratulations!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Love you, love you!
Love you!
Ready Steady / 作詞：q*Left　作曲：Giga
Ready Steady / Lyrics: q*Left, Composition: Giga
羅列苦じゃまだ　足りなくなっちゃって落とし
Listing out pains is a bother, not enough and I drop it
Are you all my base?　笑っちゃうくらい
Are you all my base? It's almost laughable
なも無いいなんて　言ったってしょうがないじゃん
Calling it "nameless" doesn't help at all, does it?
Up against the wall!
High Five!
前ならえであとについたってつまんね
Following "eyes front" is just boring
夢を語れ　ほらこの街のスタンス
Speak your dreams, that's the stance of this city
ただ見てたいだけなんてのが嘘です
Just wanting to watch is a lie
そろそろマイク頂戴
It's about time, give me the mic
どうせならもう...
If anything, make it so...
...後戻りもできないくらい　どうにかさせて
...I can't turn back anymore.
まだまだハマっていきたい段階...
I'm at the stage where I want to keep getting hooked...
...まるで恋してるみたい
...it's just like being in love.
好きになっちゃった　ちょっとさ
I've fallen for it, just a little
ならこのまま　君を連れて望むなら
Then, if you want me to take you along as we are...
どこまでも
To anywhere
Never wanna　欲しがってばかりで
Never wanna, just keep on wanting more
結構　結構　もし叶うなら
Fine, fine, if it can come true...
この先の世界を知りたい
I want to know the world that lies ahead
行きたい
I want to go
Ready Steady
ちょっとだけなら無茶だって主張　一生一等いいっしょ
I'll claim that even a little recklessness is fine, first-class forever is good, right?
この世のすべて奪っちゃうくらい
Enough to take everything in this world.
とはいえ勝手ばっかじゃどうしようもないっしょ
But being selfish all the time won't get you anywhere, right?
指はねてハイファイ
Snapping fingers, Hi-Fi.
ねえ少しはこちら向いたらどう？
Hey, why don't you look this way a bit?
気まぐれに嵌らせたいだけ
I just want to make you fall for my whims.
でも奪いたい　震わせたい
But I want to take it, I want to make it shake.
鳴り止まぬ君の燃えるハイ
Your burning high that won't stop ringing.
誰もが羨む驚異のトラック　リリックで
With lyrics on a track of wonders that everyone envies.
魅せていくからリテイクはしないで
I'll show you, so don't ask for a retake.
だからこのまま
So just like this.
君を連れて望むなら
Taking you along, if you want.
どこまでも
Anywhere.
Any Wanna　無いものねだるなら
Any Wanna, if you're asking for the impossible.
結構　結構
Fine, fine.
早くよ　夜明けて
Hurry up, let the dawn break.
鮮やかに着替え
Change into vivid clothes.
思い重い
Heavy thoughts.
熱量下げない
Don't let the heat drop.
この声も聞き落とさぬように
So you don't miss even this voice.
踊り狂え
Dance like crazy.
I want more.
Are you ready?
ならこのまま
Then just like this.
君を連れて望むなら
Taking you along, if you want.
どこまでも
Anywhere.
Any Wanna　欲しがってばかりで
Any Wanna, just constantly wanting.
結構　結構
Fine, fine.
もし叶うなら
If it comes true.
この先の未来を知りたい
I want to know the world ahead.
知りたい
I want to know.
Ready Steady.
ロボ子先輩！
Roboco-senpai!
ロボ子さーん！
Roboco-san!
おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations!
あー、ありがとうー！
Ah, thank you!
うぉうぉうぉうぉ、なに？なに？その姿はどうしてしまったんだよ！
Woah woah woah, what? What? What happened to your appearances!
あ、これ呪われた姿ですよ。
Ah, this is our cursed form.
呪われた姿。
Cursed form.
そう、呪いが解けたら隣に並べます。
Yeah, when the curse is lifted, we'll stand next to you.
三体いた。あ、まだ先なのかな？いつか並ぶの。
There were three of you. Ah, is it still a while away? Standing side by side.
まだまだ先。
Still a long way off.
やばいな、だいぶ薄っぺらくなったな。
Man, you've gotten quite flat.
マジか。
For real?
逆にいいんですよ、逆に。
It's actually good, you know? Actually.
あ、逆にね、うん。確かになんかかっこいいよ。すごい似合ってる。
Ah, actually, yeah. True, it's kinda cool. It suits you really well.
な、なんかやだー！
Wha- I don't like it!
似合ってるよ。立体になってた、立体に。
It suits you. You were 3D, 3D.
このままでもいいよ。
It's fine like this too.
やだー！
Nooo!
いやロボ子すごい快適だな。3Dで動けちゃって。
Man, Roboco is so comfortable. Being able to move in 3D.
くっそー！
Damn it!
ちょっとこの可愛いドレス着やがってー！
Hey, look at you wearing this cute dress!
本当にいい、可愛い？どうこれ。
It's really nice, is it cute? How's this?
めっちゃ可愛いです。
It's super cute.
ラプラスの紫色も入ってる。
La+'s purple is in there too.
あ、そう。ラプラスのも入ってる。
Ah, right. La+'s too.
クロヱのもここ、ほら。
Chloe's is here too, look.
いけてない？入ってる。いや、すごい。
Isn't it cool? It's there. Wow, amazing.
実は思ったんですけど。
Actually, I was thinking.
ドレスの裏地、沙花叉の私服の部分に似てません？
Doesn't the dress lining look like Sakamata's casual clothes?
やべ、ブランド一緒だわ。
Oh man, it's the same brand.
おそろっちだな、これ。
It's matching then.
やべ、バレちまった。匂わせちゃったな。
Oh no, I've been found out. I gave it away.
なんて？
What?
テレテレ。
*blushing sounds*
吾輩にも教えろ、そのブランド。
Tell me too, that brand.
ちょっとラプラスにはまだ早い、早いよ。
It's a bit too early for La+, too early.
なんでだよ！教えろよ！変わんないだろ！
Why! Tell me! It wouldn't change anything!
ラプラスにはこの一輪のバラで十分だ。
For La+, this single rose is enough.
あ、なんかちょっと嬉しい。
Ah, I'm kinda happy.
おい、ちょろいな。ちょろいぞ。
Hey, you're so easy. Too easy.
ちょっと嬉しいやないか。
I'm just a little happy.
え、でも二人とも歌ってくれてありがとう。
Anyway, thank you both for singing with me.
こちらこそありがとうございました。
Thank you as well.
いや、ちょっとね、いい女たち侍らせ...
Well, you know, having such fine women around...
いい女たち？ん？
Fine women? Hm?
自分でおっしゃたくせに酷くないですか。
Isn't it cruel after you said it yourself?
言うだけ言って酷くないですか。
Isn't it cruel to just say it and then...?
あ、合ってたかなと思って。いい女たちで。
Ah, I was wondering if it was correct. Fine women.
いい女たち。
Fine women.
でもさ、隣の女はともかく吾輩はいい女だよね。
But you know, setting the woman next to me aside, I'm a fine woman, right?
あれ？
Huh?
あれ？そうかも。
Huh? Maybe so.
えー！
Eh!
でもすっごいかっこよかったよ。
But it was really cool.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
いやもう、ロボ子さんイケボ、イケボ。
Man, Roboco-san, your voice is so cool.
本当。ダウナーでかっこよかった。
True. It was cool and moody.
嬉しいんだが。
I'm happy about that.
今度はな、ハリボテじゃなくて3Dでかっこよく歌いたいな。
Next time, I want to sing coolly in 3D, not as cutouts.
そうですね。
That's true.
一緒にライブに立ちましょう。
Let's stand on the live stage together.
立とうぜ！
Let's do it!
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
じゃあそろそろロボ子先輩、次もありますので我々は退散したいと思います。さらば。
Well, it's about time, Roboco-senpai. There's more coming up, so we'll be taking our leave. Farewell.
ありがとうー　HoloX！
Thank you, HoloX!
ありがとうございましたー！またねー！さらばー！ロボ子さんおめでとう！
Thank you! See ya! Farewell! Congratulations, Roboco-san!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
あ、めっちゃ飛んでく。めっちゃ飛んでく。
Ah, they're flying away. Flying away.
あ、裏、裏地が見えてる。あー！
Ah, the back, the lining is showing. Ahhh!
ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！
Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake up!!
ほのむにょ
Honomunyo (sleepy sounds)
わぁー！
Waa!
Fast time
Ready?
急げ 急げ
Hurry, hurry
Hurry up
Wake up!
目覚まし 仕事して
Wake up and do your job
8時 格闘中
Struggling at 8 o'clock
起きたくても 起きられない
Even if I want to wake up, I can't
だって ウダウダしたいわ
Because I want to laze around
モーベッドバカ
Geez, bed idiot
超速で洗顔だ
Washing my face at super speed
待っててね 歯磨き粉
Wait for me, toothpaste
ブレックファストの暇はなし
No time for breakfast
ラズベリーのパン くわえて
With raspberry bread in my mouth
猛烈ダッシュ いってきます
Intense dash, I'm off!
遅刻は絶対 許されない
Lateness is absolutely not allowed
だって 呼び出しメール 近づいてる
Because a calling mail is approaching
信号待ち なんかしてらんない
I can't afford to wait for the light
見逃さない 青春中
I won't miss out, in the middle of youth
止まらないわ 猛 爆走中
I won't stop, sprinting wildly
モタモタしてたら 乗り遅れるから
If you dilly-dally, you'll be left behind
ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイミーアップ！
Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake me up!
芯の鼓動に 弾み走り出せ
Bound towards the core's beat and start running
眩しい朝日 浴びて 全速力
Bathed in the bright morning sun, at full speed
間に合わないこと なんかはない
There's nothing I won't make it in time for
飛び出そう
Let's jump out
地面蹴って 腿上げて
Kick the ground, raise your thighs
汗びしょびしょで 頑張っちゃうぜ
Soaked in sweat, I'll do my best
諦めたら そこで終わる
If you give up, it ends there
無理は承知 Wake up Hurry up
Knowing it's impossible, Wake up Hurry up
ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！
Wake up!! Wake up!!
叶えたい夢とか
Like dreams I want to come true
叶えたい恋とか
Like love I want to come true
絶対 絶対 絶対 諦めない
Never, never, never give up
私のモットーだから
Because it's my motto
遅刻とかしてられない
I can't afford to be late
誰かのせいに なんかしたくない
I don't want to blame it on anyone
全ての選択肢 自分次第
All choices depend on me
眠い目 こしごし 1日が始まる
Rubbing sleepy eyes, the day begins
目的地は もっともっと先
The destination is further and further ahead
限界突破で 突き進め
Go forward by breaking through limits
ドタバタな毎日に
In the hectic daily life
負けない 負けない たまりたくない
I won't lose, won't lose, I don't want to pile up
今日は絶対に早く寝よう
Today I'll definitely go to sleep early
ああ 明日は絶対 早起きすんだ
Ah, tomorrow I'll definitely wake up early
ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイミーアップ！
Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake me up!
芯の鼓動に 弾み走り出せ
Bound towards the core's beat and start running
眩しい朝日 浴びて 全速力
Bathed in the bright morning sun, at full speed
間に合わないこと なんかはない
There's nothing I won't make it in time for
飛び出そう
Let's jump out
地面蹴って 腿上げて
Kick the ground, raise your thighs
汗びしょびしょで 頑張っちゃうぜ
Soaked in sweat, I'll do my best
諦めたら そこで終わる
If you give up, it ends there
無理は承知 Wake up Hurry up
Knowing it's impossible, Wake up Hurry up
ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！ ウェイカッ！！
Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake up!! Wake up!!
そう... ん? そう...
Sleepy noises...
ロボ子ちゃん！ロボ子ちゃん起きて！ウェーイカッ！
Roboco-chan! Roboco-chan wake up! Wake up!
う... うう...
Ugh... mumbling...
ウェーイカッ！ウェーイカッ！ウェーイカッ！
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
なに寝てるのら こんな大切な日に！
Why are you sleeping on such an important day!
うえ... なんかキンコンカンコン...
Ugh... something like 'ding dong dang'...
もう寝んじゃ ないのらよ！起きなさい！
Don't sleep anymore! Wake up!
おき、起きる！起きる！
I-I'm waking up! Waking up!
ウェーイカッ！ウェーイカッ！ウェーイカッ！
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
驚くルーナと ウェイカッ！
With a surprised Luna, Wake up!
歌ってしまったのらよ
I ended up singing, nora.
め、目覚めたわ〜！ふぅ〜！
I... I've woken up! Phew!
目覚めた、よかった〜
You woke up, thank goodness.
よかったよ〜
Glad to hear it.
てか、あれだよ、改めて...
Anyway, once again...
お、何？何？
Oh, what? What?
ロボちゃん、お誕生日おめでと〜！
Robo-chan, happy birthday!
え〜、ありがと〜！
Aw, thank you!
誕生日だぼ、今日生まれたぼ！
It's my birthday, I was born today!
そうなのよ、今日生まれたのよ、今。
That's right, you were born today. Just now.
あ、今生まれた？
Ah, just born now?
うん、今生まれた、今生まれた、今生まれた〜、みんな！
Yeah, just born, just born, just born, everyone!
おぎゃ〜！おめでたい！
Waaah! Congratulations!
おめでた〜！ありがと〜。
Happy birthday! Thank you.
というわけでね、ルーナとね、
So, with Luna,
いゔどっとさんの『Wake Up』歌わせていただきました〜！
we performed Eve-dot's "Wake Up"!
え、なんでこの曲選んだの？
Hey, why did you choose this song?
え、好きだから。
Uh, because I like it.
あ、好き、うん、あ、そう、うん。
Oh, you like it. Yeah, I see.
アイドルソングだったのにな、リハ中、そう、そう、そう。
It was an idol song, though. During rehearsal, yeah...
え、でもめちゃめちゃ歌ってて楽しかったでしょ？
But wasn't it super fun to sing?
めっちゃよかった、映えた、映えた！
It was great! It really popped!
え、映え曲だよね！映えたよ。
Yeah, it's a "pop" song! It really did.
そう、なんかセリフも多めで、めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだよね。
Yeah, it has a lot of dialogue lines too, it's really cute.
これさ、二人で歌うの初めてじゃねーの？今日。
Wait, isn't this the first time we've sung together? Today.
え、待って、確かに。二人で...
Wait, you're right. Just the two of us...
初めて歌った！
First time singing together!
横並び初めてなのよな〜
It's our first time standing side-by-side too.
え、確かに。3Dで横並び初めてだ！
Oh, for sure. First time side-by-side in 3D!
え、ここに来て初？
Wait, after all this time, our first?
いつも深夜話してんのにな。
Even though we're always talking late at night.
いつも話したりさ、色々、あの、歌ってるのに今日初めてって。
Even though we talk a lot and sing various things, today's the first time.
あれ、ま、でも確かに、3人とか4人は結構多かったから、
Wait... well, we've often been in groups of 3 or 4,
会っては、会ってはいるんだけどね。
so we *have* met...
えー、嬉しい、記念だ、記念、今日は。
Aw, I'm happy. It's a commemoration, a commemoration, today.
じゃあ、記念に写真でも撮ろうか。
Then, shall we take a photo for the occasion?
あ、撮りたい！
Oh, I want to!
おい、せっかくだからロボ子がアイドルポーズを伝授してやろう。
Hey, since we're at it, Roboco will teach you an idol pose.
アイドルポーズ？どんな？
An idol pose? What kind?
そうだ、おててをグーにします。
That's right. Make fists with your hands.
はい、グー。
Okay, fists.
顎の下に持ってきます。
Bring them under your chin.
顎の下、うん。
Under the chin, okay.
上目遣いをします。ぎゅぎゅぎゅ〜。
Look up with puppy eyes. Gyu gyu gyu~.
これがアイドルポーズなの。
This is the idol pose.
アイドルポーズ、アイドルポーズ。
Idol pose, idol pose.
あ、可愛ければいいのよな！
Ah, as long as it's cute, it's fine!
そう、可愛ければいいの。はい、撮って撮って、いいよ、いいよ。
Right, as long as it's cute. Okay, take the photo, looking good.
どうだ、これがアイドルポーズだ。分かったか？
How's that? This is the idol pose. Get it?
あ、ありがとうございます、先輩。
Ah, thank you very much, Senpai.
ありがとうございます。分かりました、これがアイドルポーズなのね。
Thank you. I see, so this is the idol pose.
これ、もう、可愛。顧客が求めるものでございます。
This is just too cute. It's what the customers want.
みんな喜んでるのらね〜
Everyone's happy, nanora~
いいかな、いいかな。
Good, good.
いやでもほんまに、え、僕たちいいカラーリングじゃないか？
But really, don't we have a great color combination?
いいよね、ピンク、可愛い。赤。
It's nice. Pink is cute. And red.
ピース！いいよね。
Peace! It's good.
いや、今日はね、本当に素敵なね、誕生日を迎えられて、本当によかったです。
Really, I'm so glad I could have such a wonderful birthday today.
ありがと〜！
Thank you!
この後も、ぜひ楽しんでください！
Please continue to enjoy the rest of the show!
ありがと〜！
Thank you!
じゃ、また遊ぼうね！ありがと〜、またね〜！
Well, let's play again! Thank you, see ya!
バイバイ！Wake Up! Wake Up! Wake Up!
Bye-bye! Wake Up! Wake Up! Wake Up!
水平線
作詞・作曲 清水 依与吏
Suiheisen (Horizontal Line)
Lyrics & Composition by Iori Shimizu
できるだけ嘘はないように
So that there are as few lies as possible
どんな時も優しくあれるように
So that I can be kind at all times
人が痛みを感じた時には
When someone feels pain
自分のことのように思えるように
So that I can feel it as if it were my own
正しさを別の正しさで
Losing a sense of righteousness
失くす悲しみにも出会うけれど
To another kind of righteousness; a sorrow I'll encounter, but...
水平線が光る朝に あなたの希望が崩れ落ちて
On a morning when the horizon glows, your hope crumbles and falls
風に飛ばされる欠片に 誰かが綺麗と呟いてる
To the fragments blown by the wind, someone whispers, "How beautiful."
悲しい声で歌いながら いつしか海に流れ着いて
While singing with a sad voice, eventually washing up on the shore
光って あなたはそれを見るでしょう
Shining, and you will see it
自分の背中は見えないのだから
Because you can't see your own back
恥ずかしからず人に尋ねるといい
Don't be ashamed to ask someone else
心は誰にも見えないのだから
Because no one can see into your heart
見えるものよりも大事にしたい
I want to cherish it more than the things I can see
…にするといい
...it would be good to...
毎日が重なることで
As the days pile up
会えなくなる人もできるけれど
There will be people you can no longer see
透き通るほど淡い夜に
In a night so pale it's almost transparent
あなたの夢が一つ叶って
One of your dreams comes true
歓声と拍手の中に
Amidst the cheers and applause
誰かの悲鳴が隠れている
Someone's scream is hidden
耐える理由を探しながら
While searching for a reason to endure
いくつも答えを抱えながら
While holding many answers
悩んで
Worrying
あなたは自分を知るでしょう
You will come to know yourself
誰の心に残ることも
Staying in no one's heart
目に焼き付くこともない今日も
Leaving no trace in anyone's eyes even today
雑音と砂音の奥で
Deep within the noise and the sound of sand
私はここだと叫んでいる
I am screaming that I am here
水平線が光る朝に
On the morning when the horizon glows
あなたの希望が崩れ落ちて
Your hopes crumble away
風に飛ばされる欠片に
At the fragments blown away by the wind
誰かが綺麗と呟いてる
Someone is muttering that they are beautiful
悲しい声で歌いながら
While singing with a sad voice
いつしか海に流れ着いて
Before long, they wash up on the sea
光って
Shining
あなたはそれを見るでしょう
You will see it
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Honeymoon Un Deux Trois
作詞・作曲: DATEKEN
Lyrics & Composition: DATEKEN
誰もいなくなった
Everyone is gone
二人だけの街に
In a town with only the two of us
機械仕掛けの時計が
A clockwork timepiece
夜の訪れ知らせる
Announces the arrival of night
夕闇が空を
The twilight colors the sky
ワイン色に染めて
In a wine-like hue
不慣れな二人を
The inexperienced pair
舞台へと誘う
Are beckoned to the stage
Chess and Whist and a natural time
あなたに魔法をあげる
I'll give you magic
Throw away and always way
その名前は蜜月
The name of it is Honeymoon
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Honeymoon Un Deux Trois
互いの指を絡めて
Intertwining our fingers
Sing a swing a sweetest time
二人の夢を奏でる
Playing out the dreams of two
Chess and Whist and a natural time
あなたに魔法をかける
I'll cast a spell on you
Throw away and always way
その名前は蜜月
The name of it is Honeymoon
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Mitsugetsu Un Deux Trois
魅惑の蜜に　耳を澄ませ
Listen closely to the enchanting honey
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Honeymoon un, deux, trois
その唇を重ねて
Let's bring our lips together
Swing, Swing, Sweetest Song
二人の愛を奏でる
Playing our love
月明りロゼを
Moonlight rosé
黄金色に照らして
Illuminating in golden hues
幼い二人は
The two children
躓きながら踊る
Dance while stumbling
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Honeymoon un, deux, trois
互いの指を絡めて
Intertwining our fingers
Swing, Swing, Sweetest Song
二人の夢を奏でる
Playing our dreams
蜜月アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Honeymoon un, deux, trois
その唇を重ねて
Let's bring our lips together
Swing, Swing, Sweetest Song
二人の愛を奏でる
Playing our love
亡國覚醒カタルシス
作詞：宝野アリカ　作曲：片倉三起也
Bokoku Kakusei Catharsis
Lyrics: Arika Takano / Composition: Mikiya Katakura
嘆きの壁は　積み上げられて
The Wailing Wall is piled up
愚かの神は　奉られる
The foolish god is worshipped
生きるは毒杯　杞憂の苦しみを
飲み干す術を　誰が授けよう
Life is a poison chalice; who shall teach us
how to drink dry the worries of anxiety?
太陽に棲むと云う賢者の鷲は
羽搏きだけが　こだまする
The sage's eagle said to live in the sun;
only the flapping of its wings echoes
この双つの眸に宿った　闇と光　その何方で
In these two eyes, darkness and light dwell; with which of them...
僕は未来を　見つめるべきなのだろう
Should I gaze into the future?
渇き切った瓦礫の街　点と線を繋ぎ合わせ
In a city of bone-dry rubble, connecting the dots and lines
意味など無い事ばかり　溢れてゆく
Meaningless things are overflowing
炎のごとき孤独　抱く体鎮めては
The flame-like loneliness, quieting the body it embraces
暗渠へと滴っていく雫
Drops dripping into the culvert
掲げる毒杯　この生は満ちても
焦がれる死の夢は流れ着く
I raise the poison chalice; though this life is full,
the longing dream of death drifts ashore
砦に喰い込む爪　孤高の鷲は
羽搏きだけが　舞い上がる
Talons digging into the fortress, the solitary eagle;
only its flapping soars high
あの蒼穹に　磔にしてくれたまえ
Please crucify me against that azure sky
天と地が結ぶ場所に僕は立つ
I stand where heaven and earth meet
果実のような記憶たちが
焼かれ爛れ抜け殻となり
Memories like fruit are burned,
inflamed, and become empty shells
あの日の魂は　何処へ行ったのだろう
Where has the soul of that day gone?
冷たい肌寄せ合って触れて　胸の傷と傷を合わせ
Pressing cold skin together, touching, matching wound to wound on our chests
再び辿るべき地図　ここに刻む
A map to be followed again, carved right here
世界は見えぬ翼　その黒影に隠された
The world is hidden within the black shadow of invisible wings
純白の一羽　射止めよ
Shoot down the one snow-white bird
生きるは祝杯　移しの享楽
渇く喘ぎも息も絶え絶えに
Life is a toast, the pleasure of a copy;
dry gasps and breath are faint
まぐわい合う慰みの掌に実る
Bearing fruit in the palms of entwining comfort
虚しさだけが膨らんで
Only emptiness expands
ああ玉砕と美しく散りゆくならば
Ah, if I were to scatter in a beautiful, glorious defeat
恍惚の先にはまだ君が居る
You are still there beyond the ecstasy
嘆きの壁は突き崩されて
The Wall of Lamentation is broken down
愚かな民は皆殺される
The foolish people are all killed
生きるは毒杯　愛する哀しみを
Living is a poisoned chalice; the sorrow of loving
飲み干す術を誰が授けよう
Who shall grant the means to drink it dry?
月下に眠ると云う　静かの海
The Sea of Tranquility, said to sleep under the moonlight
啼き声だけが舞い降りて
Only the cries descend upon it
掲げる祝杯　わが生は満ちても
Raising a toast, even if my life is full
果敢ない死の遊戯は果てもなく
The reckless game of death is endless
砦に喰い込む爪　孤高の羽
Claws digging into the fortress; solitary wings
羽搏きだけが舞い上がる
Only the flapping of wings soars high
あの蒼穹に磔にしてくれたまえ
Please crucify me against that blue sky
罪と罰を生む時代を僕は視る
I behold the era that gives birth to crime and punishment
リルビ
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Lil’bi
Lyrics/Music: PinocchioP
ねぇドクター　ヘイドクター　メンテしてよドクター
Hey Doctor, hey Doctor, maintain me, Doctor
またいつもの脳のバグ
Another brain bug as usual
ハッピー　アンラッキー　行き来するモード
Happy, unlucky, switching modes
組み立てゼンマイ式のココロ　どこだ？
Where is my wind-up heart?
ZZZZ ZZZ...
Tick Tick Tick Tick Tock Tock
おっかしいねおっかしいね　くっだらないね　Ya Ya
It's strange, it's strange, it's trivial, Ya Ya
ワケないね　ワケないね　ハイスペックなんで
No problem, no problem, because I'm high-spec
最先端のPON　やらなきゃ損
Cutting-edge clumsiness, it's a loss if you don't do it
ドキドキが止まりそ　ネジ巻いて
My heartbeat is about to stop, wind my spring
なんてゆーかエブリデイ　ネジ巻いて　ネジ巻いてよ
Like, every day, wind the spring, wind the spring for me
ちょっとだけね　ちょ　ちょ　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, ju-ju-just a little bit
ピポパポ鳴らして　夢を製造（つく）る
Making beeps and boops, manufacturing dreams
ちょっとだけね　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
でもちょっとだけじゃそのうち足んなくなるかも
But just a little bit might not be enough soon
リルビ リルビ リルビモ
Lil’bi, Lil’bi, Lil’bimo
ZZZZ ZZZ...
Tick Tick Tick Tick Tock Tock
ねぇドクター　メンテしたの？　ドクター
Hey Doctor, did you maintain me? Doctor
Wow Wow
Take a look around　てか分からん　ワケ分からん
Take a look around, or rather I don't get it, I don't get it at all
次元の呪いなんて祓（はら）おう
Let's exorcise the dimensional curse
なんだかおっかないねおっかないね　とんでもないね　Ya Ya
It's kind of scary, it's scary, it's outrageous, Ya Ya
これはもうテクノだ　テクノロジーだ
This is already techno, it's technology
三原則だってメモってるもん
I even have the Three Laws noted down
理解（わか）ったらその手ですぐ巻いて
If you understand, wind it right away with that hand
リルビ
Lil’bi
病んじゃっても笑って　ネジ巻いて　ネジ巻いてよ
Even if I get sick, laugh and wind the spring, wind the spring for me
ちょっとだけね　ちょ　ちょ　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, ju-ju-just a little bit
キミがミスっても笑わせてあげる
Even if you make a mistake, I'll make you laugh
ちょっとだけね　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
ほらTake a look around Take a look around
See, take a look around, take a look around
アイデンティティ　アップデートして
Update your identity
ドモアリガト　ココロから
Thank you very much, from the bottom of my heart
リルビ　リルビ
Lil’bi, Lil’bi
ピポパポピポパポピ
Pipopapopipopapopi
カラクリしゃしゃんせ
Mechanical gimmick, come on in
起きて起きて　電気羊
Wake up, wake up, electric sheep
こちらに来やしゃんせ
Come over here
その前にひとまずネジ巻いて
Before that, for now, wind the spring
なんてゆーかエブリデイ　ネジ巻いて　ネジ巻いてよ
Like, every day, wind the spring, wind the spring for me
ちょっとだけね　ちょ　ちょ　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, ju-ju-just a little bit
オーダーメイド　夢を製造（つく）る
Order-made, manufacturing dreams
ちょっとだけね　ほんのちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a tiny bit
もうバグでもなんでもいいけど明日もちょっとだけ巻いて
I don't care if it's a bug or whatever, just wind it a little bit tomorrow too
ちょっとだけね　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
こんな毎日も悪くないよ
A daily life like this isn't so bad
ちょっとだけね　ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
でもちょっとだけじゃそのうち足んなくなるかも
But just a little bit might not be enough soon
リルビ リルビ リルビ リルビモ
Lil’bi, Lil’bi, Lil’bi, Lil’bimo
ZZZZ ZZZ...
Tick Tick Tick Tick Tock Tock
More
リルビ little bit
Little Bit
ということで、新曲『リルビ』でしたー！
And so, that was my new song, "Little Bit"!
え、どう？びっくりした？
So, how was it? Were you surprised?
今回はですね、ちょっとかっこいい曲をやってみたくて、
This time, I wanted to try a cool song,
てにをはさんに楽曲をお願いしたんですけど、
so I asked Teniwoha-san to compose it,
え、どう？
well, how is it?
なんか結構リズムカルで癖になるイメージでね、
With a rhythmic and addictive image,
あの、ボクらしい曲を作ってもらったんですけど、
they made a song that's very "me",
めちゃくちゃかっこよくないですか！？
isn't it super cool!?
そう、歌い方もね、すごく悩んでね、
Yeah, I also worried a lot about how to sing it,
今回こちらが完成形だったのですけれども、
and this is the final version,
みんなどうだったー！？
what did you all think!?
いや、ボクも大好き！
Man, I love it too!
こちらはですね、なんと5月の23日、
This song, actually, on May 23rd,
24時からリリースされるので、ぜひ買ってください！
will be released at midnight, so please buy it!
ちょっとあの、ランキングにも乗りたい！
I want to get on the rankings!
みんな頼んだぞー！
I'm counting on you all!
そしてそして、みんなお楽しみ、
And then, what you've all been waiting for,
ボクの誕生日記念グッズは...こちらです！
my birthday memorial goods are... these!
ドドーン！
Tada!
はい、お待たせしました。ついにボクも出します、
Yes, thanks for waiting. I'm finally releasing one too,
おっぱいマウスパッドをね！へへっ。
an "oppai" mousepad! Hehe.
こちら、らっち先生の描き下ろしウェディングのボク！
This is me in a wedding dress drawn by Racchi-sensei!
え、どうこれ？艶っぽいでしょ？
So, how's this? It's kind of sexy, right?
ふふっ。そしてね、え、ボク描き下ろしのピンバッジも出します！
Fufu. And, I'm also releasing pin badges drawn by me!
見てみて。
Take a look.
こっちはね、ちょっと可愛いね、デフォルメでね。
These are a bit cute, in chibi style.
そして meditative そして...ドドーン！
And then... tada!
ボクのぬいぐるみまで出ちゃいます！
I'm even releasing a plushie of myself!
これ結構ね、大きいんですよ、だいぶ。
This is actually quite big.
え、ボクお正月衣装でね、大きいリボンのついた、え、ボクなんですけれども、
It's me in my New Year's outfit with a big ribbon,
可愛がってほしいなー！へへっ。
I hope you'll cherish it! Hehe.
そして、これだけでは終わりません！
And that's not all!
ASMRボイスも出します！
I'm also releasing ASMR voices!
え、めちゃ久しぶりの収録ボイスなんですけれども、
These are the first recorded voices in quite a while,
ボクだけでしか味わえないボクとの
I've recorded some lovey-dovey situations with me
イチャイチャシチュエーションを更新して収録したので、ぜひ聞いてみてね！へへっ。
that you can only experience here, so please give them a listen! Hehe.
はい、そして、全部買ってくれた人には、複製サイン＆メッセージ入りの
Yes, and for those who buy the full set, you'll get a
らっち先生描き下ろしのポストカードがついてくるよ！
postcard drawn by Racchi-sensei with a duplicated signature and message!
数量限定で、今回もボクの直筆サインがついてくる！
And for a limited quantity, it'll come with my actual handwritten signature again!
みんなこの後すぐ、準備はいいかー！？
Is everyone ready for right after this!?
ゲットしてくれるよね？
You'll get it, right?
どれもね、丹精込めて考えてるので、ロボ子ゲットだぜ！してってね。
I put a lot of heart into thinking about all of these, so please "get a Roboco"!
ぬいぐるみね、ちなみにめちゃめちゃ可愛い。
By the way, the plushie is super cute.
そう、色合いも今回ね、可愛く作ってみました。
Yeah, I tried to make the colors cute this time too.
ボクの誕生日なんですけれども、
Even though it's my birthday,
なんと！これだけじゃないんです！
actually! that's not all!
なんと！ボクの公式LINEスタンプが出ます！
Actually! My official LINE stamps are coming out!
そして、なんとこちら、動くんです！うわーい！
And, these are actually animated! Yay!
こちら、いぬいぬのふあさんに描いてもらったんですけど、見てこれ、めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Inu-inu no fua-san drew these, look, they're so cute!
そう、LINEスタンプ、どうしてもね、動かしたくて動かしたくて、
Yeah, I really, really wanted animated LINE stamps,
今回いぬいぬのふあさんにお願いしたんですけど、
so I asked Inu-inu no fua-san this time,
え、これ可愛すぎない！？
aren't these too cute!?
「ボポーンボポーン」がサムネなんだけど。
The thumbnail is "Bopon Bopon".
ね、いっぱい、あの友達を煽る時とかね、
Right, when you're teasing your friends or whatever,
ボクの可愛さをとりあえず友達にたくさんたくさん見せて、「可愛い」って言わせてください。
please show off my cuteness to your friends a lot and make them say I'm cute.
友達いない人はね、作れるおまじない...
For those who don't have friends, I've cast a spell to make some...
「友達ポッ」はい、おまじないをね、掛けといたので、ぜひこれで買って買ってみよう、送り付けてみよう。
"Friends po!" Yes, I've cast a spell, so please buy these and try sending them.
ね、いや、まじで可愛いな、ボクスタンプ。早くロボ子も使いたい。うん。
Right, man, my stamps are seriously cute. I want to use them soon too. Yeah.
ということで、グッズ告知でした！
And so, that was the merchandise announcement!
みんなゲットしてよねー！
Everyone, make sure to get them!
◇出演◇ ロボ子さん
Cast: Roboco-san
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna
ラプラス・ダークネス
La+ Darknesss
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
◇サムネイル制作◇ 里人B
Thumbnail Creation: Sato-bito B
◇ロゴ制作◇ ゆーや
Logo Creation: Yu-ya
◇映像制作◇ chaosgroove
Video Production: chaosgroove
◇振付◇ まいどん
Choreography: Maidon
@小豆
@azuki
いりぽん先生
Iripon-sensei
いりあん大王
Irian Daiou
ロボ子爆誕2022
Roboco Bakutan 2022